淘宝搜索店铺：我爱美剧创意周边
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  zeoyyyyy   Eunice油腻希   帅气男子赛太公
翻译:  洗七里   亲爱的小饭
校对:  偷钱偷心赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第十九集
最新海外影视剧下载
微信扫描
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔
听着
Listen up.
如果你们谁敢当二五仔
Any of youse goes stool-pigeon on me,
就等着穿进芝加哥大衣[棺材]吧
you'll find yourself in a Chicago overcoat.
亲爱的  你不会一直到婚礼现场
Honey, you're not gonna talk like that
都要这样说黑话吧
all the way to the wedding, are you?
到那座天桥都忍不了
Or all the way to that overpass?
至少你还挺好看的
Hey, at least you look cute.
谁替我挑的衣服
Who picked my outfit?
我啊
I did.
我爸和洛林决定办一个1920年代主题婚礼
My dad and Lorraine decided to have a 1920s-themed wedding.
多么浪漫的时代啊
Such a romantic time.
是啊  过度开垦沙尘暴  3K党  禁酒令
Yeah, dust bowls, the Klan, Prohibition.
我...我相信他们会提供酒的
Oh, I'm -- I'm sure they'll have alcohol.
自助加油吗
Self-serve?
我猜油猴们肯定在后面扔[杀]骰子玩呢
I guess the grease monkeys must be out back shooting dice.
能让他们来把我们杀了吗
Can they come out here and shoot us?
天啊  低头
Oh, God, look down.
海莉
Haley?
我们要去参加一个高档的地方  行吗
We're going somewhere fancy, okay?
哪里  过去吗
Where, the past?
你好啊  吉米
Hi, Kimmy.
你也跟我们一样不想乔装打扮吗
You didn't feel like dressing up, too?
想要你们美丽的招子忘记见到过
What do you say those pretty peepers of yours
著名的黑帮老大  菲林杰
never saw the famous gangster Phillinger
改自1930年代的知名银行劫匪与黑帮分子约翰·迪林杰
和他的前妓女接应车手要多少钱呢
and his ex-prostitute getaway driver?
我看...十块大洋应该...
I think a, uh -- a sawbuck should do the --
太大张了  我去换点零钱
That's too much. I'm gonna get some change.
祝你们盛装日开心
Enjoy dress-up day.
老妈  你得管管你男人
Mom, you need to control your man.
我可受不了听这角色说话一整天
I cannot listen to this character all day.
你们了解老爸  也了解老爸的老爸
Guys, you know your dad. You know your dad's dad.
我们面对的是神秘的傻瓜力量
We are up against unimaginable forces of goofy.
记得他是因为爱才这样做的就行了
Just remember he does it out of love.
条子来了  我们快闪人吧
It's Johnny Law! Let's hot-foot it!
菲尔
Phil!
这什么情况
What the hell is all this?
我接了一个辣酱的急单
I got a rush order for my sauce,
我平常的那个厨房被订走了
and the kitchen that I usually use was booked,
所以我只能全部自己做
so I have to do everything myself.
我昨晚好像没睡好
You know, I think I slept funny last night.
别这样  我知道请你帮忙也是白搭
No, don't. I know better than to ask for your help.
那就好  我还要去打高尔夫呢
Ah, good, 'cause I have a tee time.
能顺路捎上我去取毕业舞会的燕尾服吗
On the way, could you take me to pick up my prom tux?
听着像你爱做的事情啊
That sounds like something you'd love to do.
我的确非常不想去
I so don't want to do that.
我明年就70岁了
I'm turning 70 next year.
我知道  我状态很好
I know -- I look great.
这把年纪的特权之一就是
One of the few perks of getting up there
可以毫无愧疚地直接拒绝别人
is the ability to say no without guilt.
"能送我去机场吗"  不行
"Can I have a ride to the airport?" No.
我有兴趣看你外甥女的独奏会吗
Do I want to see your niece's recital?
没有
Nuh-unh.
"想要参加马拉松竞走来结束全球..."
"Want to do a walk-a-thon to end global --"
你就别白费唇舌了
I'm gonna stop you right there.
昨晚有人进我房间吗
Was anyone in my room last night?
我昨晚把你安顿睡下后就没了
Not after I tucked you in.
很好  我房间有怪物
Great. I have a monster.
我想你肯定搞错了
I'm sure you're mistaken.
没有  今晚我上床睡觉前  一定要抓住它
Nope. And we have to catch him before I go to bed tonight.
乔  世界上没有怪物
Joe, there's no such thing as monsters.
冷静  我没打算叫你帮忙
Calm down. I'm not gonna ask you to help.
看样子今年我可以享清福了
Shaping up like a pretty good year.
早餐吃蛋糕吗  这才像话嘛
Cake for breakfast? Now we're talking.
别  别碰
No, don't touch that!
那是为胡娇叔叔今晚的
I'm making that for Uncle Pepper's
化妆派对准备的
costume party tonight.
主题是著名电影角色二人组
The theme is famous movie duos.
小爸和我要扮成《荒野猎人》里的小李子与熊
Daddy and I are going as Leo and the "Revenant" Bear.
名演员莱昂纳多·迪卡普里奥在2015年的电影
对了
You know what?
小帕哪儿去了
Where is Pam?
她说她两小时前就能到
She said she was gonna be here two hours ago.
她完全不尊重别人的时间
She has no respect for anyone else's time.
她说她要过来住一两天
You know, she says she's gonna pop in for a "Short stay."
我们就好像得重新安排我们的生活了一样
It's like we're just supposed to rearrange our lives?
我花了很长时间才终于明白这个道理
It's taken me a long time, but I've finally learned
一提到小卡姐姐的事情
that when it comes to Cam's sister,
我说的任何话都可以并且会被用来打我的脸
anything I say can and will be used against me.
你说我们是不是应该让酒保
Do you think maybe we should, you know,
别再卖酒给小帕了
have the bartender cut Pam off?
天啊  她有点要发酒疯了
Oh, God, you know what? She is getting a little bit messy.
小帕  米奇尔觉得你可能...
Uh, Pam, Mitchell thinks you're kind of
在让自己出丑
making a fool out of yourself.
去死吧  米奇尔
Go to hell, Mitchell!
你麻利儿地快去死吧
You go straight to hell!
女王陛下终于大驾光临了
Well, her majesty has finally arrived.
我能感觉到你有多生气
I can sense how angry you are.
我知道  我知道  我迟到了
I know. I know. I'm late.
没有  家人永远不算迟到
No, there's no late when you're family.
虽然米奇尔刚刚还在说
Although Mitchell was just saying --
什么风把你吹来了
What brings you into town?
当模特
Modeling.
你说什么  当模特吗
I'm sorry. Modeling?
素人模特
Real-person modeling.
在老家  他们把我放到饲料商店的广告牌上
Back home, they put me on a billboard for the feed store,
结果大受欢迎
and I caught the bug.
下一站  好莱坞
Next stop -- Hollywood.
好吧  那你要在城里待多久
Okay. So how long are you gonna be in town?
谁知道呢
Well, who's to say?
我还希望是知道呢
Well, I was hoping it'd be you.
梦想是没有期限的
You can't put a date on a dream.
说到这个
‭Speaking of,
我得去参加一个试镜
we need to take me to an audition,
我有点紧张  所以我希望你俩
and I'm a little jittery, so I was hoping you guys
能陪我去  给我点精神支持
would want to ride along for moral support.
其实  米奇尔和我有个...
Oh, actually, Mitchell and I have a r--
我们今天很忙  是不是啊  米奇尔
We have a really busy day. Isn't that right, Mitchell?
对啊
Uh, yeah.
不会花很长时间的  快走吧
Oh, this won't take long. Let's go.
在路上  我还可以练习一下我的关节痛表情
On the ride over, I can practice my joint pain grimaces.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
很好啊  很好
I am! I am!
我知道  很好  很厉害
Oh, yeah, I know. You're good. You're good.
又来
Again?!
乔好久都没用过这个勾衣服的破摇篮
Joe hasn't slept in that chewed-up sweater snagger
但歌洛莉亚不让我扔那孩子碰过的
in years, but Gloria won't let me get rid of anything
任何东西  我需要个计划
the kid has ever touched, so I needed a plan.
幸运的是  当你拒绝一切的时候
Fortunately, when you say no to everything,
就腾出了时间来构思绝妙计划
it frees up time to concoct ingenious schemes.
看  乔  哪都没有怪物
Look, Joe, there's no monsters anywhere.
床底下没有
There's nothing underneath the bed,
帐篷里也没有
nothing inside the teepee.
你们确定吗
Are you sure?
当然  怪物需要藏身之处
Yes, monsters need places to hide.
他们不像邪灵
They're not like the evil spirits,
就围绕在我们身边
which are all around us.
-什么  -没有  啥也没有  宝贝
- What? - ‭No, no, nothing, baby.
-啥也没有  -看  我的窗户开着
- Nothing. - Look, my window's open.
可能他就是从窗户进来的
Maybe that's how he got in.
不可能
Impossible.
如果他经过房顶
If he came across the roof,
就会有破损的瓦片或怪物的脚印或...
there'd be broken tiles or monster prints or...
我的压花钱夹
My monogrammed money clip.
我昨晚从乔的
I snuck in through Joe's
窗户爬进来  因为过了门禁时间
window last night because it was past curfew,
我肯定是把钱夹落在屋顶了
and I must have dropped my clip on the roof.
我得在妈妈看见之前把它捡回来
I needed to get it before mom saw.
我可不能被禁足
I can't afford to get grounded.
大卫·赛德瑞斯在工作日的晚上
David Sedaris is coming to Barnes and Noble
知名作家与单口相声演员
要来巴诺书店演出
on a school night.
我可以到房顶上看看有没有怪物的口水
I guess I can go out on the roof and check for monster slobber.
-好的  -不
- Okay. ‭- No!
如果他从房顶上掉下来摔死了
If he falls from the roof and dies,
他的幽魂就会缠着你一辈子
his ghost will haunt you forever.
天啊  我可不想要有幽魂
Oh, boy. I do not need a ghost.
曼尼  来车库里帮我个忙
Manny, help me out in the garage.
我能对我不愿做的事说不吗
Do I get to say no to things I don't want to do?
不能  在你这年纪  拒绝人会讨人厌
No, at your age, it's unlikable.
而在我这年纪  拒绝人会讨人喜
At my age, it's delightful.
你能帮我把那些复活节装饰物拿下来吗
Can you get those Easter decorations down for me?
不知道你还记得不
I don't know if you remember,
最近我的背一直疼
but my back's been bothering me lately.
我需要先换个衣服吗
Uh, do I need to change my shirt?
那儿看起来蛛网密布
It looks cobwebby up there.
不用  就拉一下
No, just give it a tug.
我都没意识到那个水泥砖这么差一点
You know, I never realized how close to the edge
就会砸到了这个漂亮的摇篮上
that cinder block is to falling right on this beautiful crib.
见了鬼了  开什么玩笑
Son of a...! You got to be kidding me!
我靠
Come on!
好热闹的场面
Quite the shindig, huh?
小傻子们去歇歇腿吧
You mooks cool your heels.
小爷我去给美人儿拿点烈酒
I'll grab some hooch for this parakeet.
菲尔  为什么我们是唯一穿成这样的
Phil, why are we the only ones in costume?
小宝贝说的没错  哪里不太对头
Oh, you're right, doll. Something's screwy.
请柬上明明写着  "可选着帮派戏服"
The invitation clearly said "Gangster attire optional."
可选着
Optional?!
你这个傻子真这么穿了
You dumbasses actually did it!
杰里  快拍
Jerry, get this!
不  杰里  别拍
No, Jerry, don't get this.
各位  这是洛林的儿子  雷
Uh, everyone, this is Lorraine's son, Ray.
母女  我最喜欢的搜索类别
Mother-daughter -- My favorite search category.
按道理你不是应该在
Shouldn't you be partially upright
"男人成长度表"上较偏后的位置了吗
on a "Stages of man" chart somewhere?
-什么  -是的
- What? ‭- Yeah.
亲爱的  你现在听着
Honey, you need to hear this right now.
你的家人很难堪
Your family's embarrassed.
我们是唯一这么穿的
We're the only ones in costumes.
你总是陷我们于这种境地
You do this all the time.
我还穿着羊毛内裤呢
I'm wearing wool underwear.
这是你为了符合历史自己选穿的
That's an extra step you chose to take.
对不起  我以为这很好玩
I'm sorry. I thought this would be fun.
但你觉得好玩的对我们来说很恐怖
Yes, but your idea of fun is often our idea of a horror show.
当你开热狗车到学校接我时
When you picked me up from school in that hot dog car.
在我的毕业典礼上
Repeatedly screaming,
不断大喊 "这才对嘛"时
"That's what I'm talking about!" at my graduation.
踩着高跷去我的科学展览会
Walking into my science fair on stilts.
你的作品是长脚[爸爸]蛛  我没得选啊
Your exhibit was on daddy longlegs. I had no choice!
亲爱的  你一直都有选择
Oh, honey, you always have a choice.
只是你总选错误的那个而已
You just keep making the wrong ones.
兄弟们
Guys.
别走啊
Come on, now.
看  是漂亮男孩邓菲
Well, look, it's Pretty Boy Dunphy.
横行于1930年代的美国知名银行劫匪"漂亮男孩弗洛伊德"
爸爸  你看起来也很棒
Looking good yourself, Pops.
你怎么样
How, uh -- How you doing?
我准备好了我的戒指  我的誓词
Well, I got my rings, got my vows.
万事俱备只欠逃婚路子
Now all I need is a way to escape.
快来人啊  帮帮我
Please, someone help.
我开玩笑呢
I'm kidding, of course.
实际上  我一直很期待再婚
Actually, I'm really looking forward to being married.
那你拿着这行李袋子干嘛
Then -- Then what's with the getaway bag?
我想请你帮我
Oh, I got to ask you to help me out
来实施我这个惊喜
with what I think is a doozy of a surprise.
过来
Come here.
听我说  仪式举行中  当你问
Get this -- Mid-ceremony, you know, when you ask
有人反对吗的时候
if anyone has any objections?
我会拿出
‭I'm gonna pull out
一个冲锋枪  让你跳过那部分
a Tommy gun and tell you to skip that part.
哎哟我滴妈  我喜欢
Sweet maple syrup. I like it.
还不止如此呢
I'm just getting warmed up.
我准备了脚本  道具枪  漆弹
I got a script, prop guns, exploding paint capsules.
我还雇了本地剧院的几个演员来帮忙
I even hired a few of the local theater people to help out.
洛林同意这件事吗
And, uh -- And Lorraine's cool with all this?
这就是最棒的地方  她根本不知道
That's the beauty part. She doesn't know a thing about it.
80%的喜剧都是惊喜
80% of comedy is surprise.
剩下的20%是文字哏
The other 20% is wordplay.
怎么了  儿子
Something wrong, son?
我觉得这可能不是个好主意
I think this might be a terrible idea.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
洛林有可能是比较传统的新娘子
Lorraine might be one of those old-fashioned brides
不想自己的婚礼上还得进行尸体清点
that doesn't want a body count on her special day.
爸  咱俩喜欢玩儿
Dad, you and I like to have fun,
但不是每个人像咱俩一样
but not everybody's like us.
有些人  有些人觉得
Some people -- Some people think
咱们的招牌幽默让人难堪
our brand of humor is embarrassing.
你说得对  有时候我的确有点过火
Oh, you're right. Maybe I do overdo it.
我记得在你受洗仪式上
I remember your mother was really ticked off at me
我一直假装圣水很烫
at your baptism when I kept pretending the holy water
你妈妈就很恼火
was boiling. ‭
好吧  我们今天就不做什么疯狂事了
Okay, we don't have to do anything crazy today.
-放心吧  -谢谢  爸爸
- Don't worry about it. - Thanks, Pops.
不过  你还是会按我们说好的那样
But, wait, you're still gonna do my funeral
帮我筹备丧礼的吧
the way we talked about, right?
播放那段你猛敲棺材盖
That recording of you banging on that piece of wood
大喊"放我出来"的录音
screaming, "Let me out of here!"
我没办法亲眼看到那一幕  真是可惜
It's a real shame I'm gonna miss that.
-你在干吗  -曼尼刚才制造的那场意外
- What are you doing? - That accident that Manny caused earlier
快把我吓死了  于是我决定
gave me quite a start, so I figured
把所有东西搬出来  用更安全的方式摆放回去
I'd pull everything out and put it back in a safer fashion.
歌洛莉亚  你能帮我插好这个插头吗
Gloria, could you plug this in for me?
我想给部分杂物吸一下尘
I want to dust off some of this stuff.
你叫人家出来外面  就为了这事吗
Did you call me outside just for that?
我的背不舒服啊
I got a back situation.
曼尼应该提起过吧
Maybe Manny mentioned it.
不  插错了
Oh, no! Wrong cord!
你都干了什么
What have you done?
天啊  乔的婴儿床貌似彻底报废了
Geez, it seems like Joe's crib's damaged beyond repair!
不不  没事啊
No, no, it's fine.
它不过是像玩"青蛙过河"  跳到了对面
It just Froggered across the street.
先放在那儿吧  明天收垃圾的人会来
Leave it there. The garbage man is coming tomorrow.
那你没意见吗
And you're fine with that?
你明明对跟那孩子有关的东西都很留恋
You're attached to everything related to that kid.
是啊  但我一点都不留念那张破床
Yeah, but not to that stupid crib.
你知道我被这张床弄坏了多少件衣服吗
Do you know how many clothes I've ruined walking by it --
有美美的裙子  毛衣  还有一双高跟鞋
nice dresses, sweaters, a pair of high heels?
你怎么有办法勾坏高跟鞋呢
How do you snag a pair of high heels?
我用脚踢那破玩意儿啊  不然呢
I kicked that stupid thing. How else?
我的陷阱起作用了  我抓到了那只怪物
My trap worked! I caught the monster!
你落入我手中了  大怪物
I got you now, monster!
等等  别动手  是我  曼尼
Wait, wait, wait, stop! It's me -- Manny.
拿出证据  我喜欢吃蔬菜吗
Prove it. Do I like vegetables?
蘸了番茄酱才肯吃
Only with ketchup.
曼尼  你怎么会在这里
Manny, what are you doing here?
我只是要找个地方
Uh, I just needed a place to practice
为毕业舞会练习新舞步
some new dance moves for the prom.
跳吧
Do it.
什么
What?
跳新舞步给我看
Do the dance moves.
不得不说  你跳得挺好
I have to admit that that is very good.
但我知道你在说谎
But I know that you're lying.
好吧
Fine.
昨晚在房间里的人是我
I was the one in here last night.
我从窗户爬进来的  因为我违反了宵禁
I came in through the window because I broke curfew.
我的钱夹掉了
I dropped my money clip,
我只是想把它找回来
and I was just trying to get it back.
你今晚别想去看大卫·赛德瑞斯了
Forget about going to David Sedaris.
我错了  乔
I was wrong, Joe.
这个房间里的确有一只怪物
There is a monster in this room.
当素人模特最关键的一点
The key to real-person modeling
是不能太吸引目光而模糊了焦点
is not to attract a lot of attention to yourself.
这张是我在考虑要不要买车
This is me thinking about buying a car.
这张是我有牙疼  很明显了
This is me with a toothache, obviously.
这张就是我很机智的样子
Oh, this is me smart.
-你刚说什么  米奇尔  -我什么都没说
- What was that, Mitchell? - I didn't say anything.
我好像听到你说  我们今天很忙
I thought you said something about that we had a busy day.
不  不  我很开心能在这里
No. No, I'm just happy to be here
见证她事业开始腾飞的时刻
watching a career get launched.
是啊
Oh. ‭Yeah.
他们叫到我名字时  喊我一声
Hey, tell me if they call my name.
我去压制一下我的美貌
I'm gonna go pretty down.
好的
Mm. ‭Okay.
你说她过分不
Can you believe her?
她就这么闯进我们的生活  觉得我们理应
She just barges into our life and expects us
放下自己的事情  支持她这个不切实际的梦想
to drop everything and invest in this crazy dream.
她演这个刚弄坏了拖把的人  的确惟妙惟肖
Well, she really does look like someone who just broke her mop.
够了  你到底怎么回事
Okay, what is going on with you?
我不会再这么做了  小卡
I'm not doing it anymore, Cam, okay?
你太害怕了  不敢反抗你大只又可怕的姐姐
Okay, you're too afraid to confront your big, scary sister,
所以你利用我来当坏人
so you use me to do it.
我不干了
Well, I'm out, okay?
除非你学会如何反抗她
Until you learn how to confront her yourself,
否则你从她那儿永远得不到
you're never gonna get the respect from her
你明显超想要的尊重
that you clearly crave.
你知道吗  我一点都不怕她好吗
Okay, you know what? I am not in the least bit intimidated by her.
"她"是谁
"Her" who?
变装戏服店的女店员啦
Oh, the lady at the costume store that,
米奇尔正催我马上去
uh, M-Mitchell's pressuring me to go
那家店里取戏服
pick up the costumes right now.
好吧  我这就去  米奇尔
I go-- Okay, I'm going, Mitchell.
天啊  急什么
My gosh. My gosh.
给我一块钱硬币
Hey, give me a dollar
我要在自动贩卖机买口香糖
so I can get me some gum.
-给你  -谢谢
- Here. - ‭Thank you.
天啊  你太完美了
My God, you're perfect.
我要火了
It's happening!
你真是太平凡太路人了
You're absolutely unremarkable!
泰瑞  快出来
Terry, get out here!
这次别又是假...
This better not be another false...
我无法不把视线从他脸上移开
I can't not take my eyes off him.
我不是来试镜的
Oh, I'm -- I'm not here to audition.
再说一遍
Say that again.
对  我已经忘了你刚刚说什么了
Yes, I've already forgotten what you said.
他就是上帝用龙套脸模板做出的成品吧
When they made him, they kept the mold.
你在看我吗  你在看我吗
Are you looking at me? Are you looking at me?
拜托告诉我你是在练习电影台词
Please tell me you're doing a scene from a movie
而不是真的不知道镜子是什么
and not confused about what a mirror is.
亲爱的  那是什么
Hi, honey. What's that?
一袋塑料枪
A bag of plastic guns.
我爸本来在婚礼上安排了一场疯狂的大戏
My dad was planning this crazy stunt at the wedding
洛林完全不知情
that Lorraine didn't even know about.
连剧本什么的都准备好了
There's a whole script for it and everything.
别担心  我已经劝阻他了
Don't worry. I talked him out of it.
今天不会再让邓菲家的人难堪了
No more embarrassing the Dunphys today.
我听到你们说的话  我真的很抱歉
I heard what you guys said, and I'm -- I'm truly sorry.
快问快答
Oh, quick.
珍妮弗·洛佩兹偷了乔恩·洛维兹什么绰号
What nickname did Jennifer Lopez steal from Jon Lovitz?
都是好莱坞知名艺人
名字缩写都可以是J-洛
J...  算了
J-- Never mind.
你好  对  是戒指
Hello? Yes, the rings.
他居然没说"J-啰"这个烂哏
Wow. He didn't say "J-Lo."
他刚听到了警笛声  也没有说
He also heard that siren and didn't say,
"接我的车来了"
"There's my ride."
老爸是不是被我们搞坏了
Did we break dad?
你们什么时候见过他
And when was the last time you saw him
拿起一罐发泡奶油
pick up a can of whipped cream
却不演"我有狂犬病"口吐白沫那一出
and not do his "I've got rabies" gag?
我的天  是不是矫枉过正了
Oh, my God. Did we go too far?
我们他把搞笑的一面给弄没了
Have we knocked the fun out of him?
才没有  不能这么想
No, no, no. Stop this thinking.
我们只差一步就能拥有一个正常的老爸了
We are this close to having a normal dad,
你们不能半途而废
and you are not ruining it.
各位  我能占用克莱尔一会儿吗
Hey, guys, can I have Claire for a second?
当然
Sure.
受不了  他们要在我们隔壁过新婚之夜吗
Ew, they're spending their wedding night right next door?
别慌  你能听到的最大动静
Calm down. The loudest noise you're gonna hear
不过是爷爷从椅子上起身而已
is Grandpa getting out of a chair.
你看起来美极了
You look great.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
这都是我第四次结婚了
Well, you'd think on my fourth marriage,
还以为不会那么紧张呢
I wouldn't be this nervous.
我猜嫁人永远不是件轻松的事
Ah, I guess it never gets easier.
我还记得我的婚礼
I remember my wedding.
我紧张得肚子里像装了乱飞的蝴蝶
My stomach was filled with butterflies.
与海莉
And Haley.
我总是嫁给很严肃的男人
I've always married such serious men.
但弗兰克可一点都不严肃
Frank is not that at all.
我知道  但如果你能忽略那一点
Oh, I know, but if you can see past that.
什么忽略
Past that?
是啊  他也有很多优点的
Yeah, he's got a lot of wonderful qualities, too.
亲爱的  不是的
Oh, sweetie, you're missing it.
我的所有前夫都是很严肃的成功人士
All my ex-husbands were accomplished, serious men,
但无聊得要死
but bone-dry.
而弗兰克每天都能逗得我乐开怀
A day hasn't gone by that Frank hasn't made me laugh.
希望我能不负他的幽默
I hope I keep up.
不过我说的你肯定都懂
Oh. ‭But who am I telling?
你也幸运嫁了邓菲男儿
You got lucky, too.
胜利的滋味
Sweet victory!
等一下
Okay, wait, wait.
-冲啊  -不要
- Charge! - No, no, no!
不许弄到我头发上
Not my hair!
你们这是在玩什么
Hey, hey, hey, hey. What's going on?
没什么  我们在用防怪物的漆
Oh, nothing. We're painting Joe's wall
重刷乔的墙来保护他
with monster repellent to protect him.
看起来你们玩得挺开心的
Looks like you're having fun, huh?
别担心  我们不会叫你做任何事的
Don't worry. We're not gonna ask you to do anything.
刷好墙角的秘诀是
The trick to the corners is if you --
我们知道
Yeah, yeah, we got it.
去给你自己倒杯酒喝吧
Go fix yourself a drink!
"去给你自己倒杯酒喝吧"
"Fix yourself a drink."
-就是那  -就是那  乔
- Right there. - Right there, Joe.
拒绝别人有这么个缺点
The thing about saying no --
如果你总是拒绝别人
You say it too much...
就再也没人找你一起做任何事了
people just stop asking.
你偷走了我的梦想
You stole my dream.
你别再这么说了行吗
Okay, would you please stop saying that?
如果不是你用你出众的平庸
If you hadn't distracted those ninnies
影响了那些笨蛋的判断  他们就会让我
with your striking regularness, they would have put me
出演全国电视广告  结果我们谁都没份
in a national TV ad campaign instead of neither of us!
你为什么冲我发火
Why are you flipping out?
我根本没和你争啊
I-I am not in competition with you.
所以你觉得我是疯婆子撒泼是吗
Oh, so now you think I'm crazy?
不是的
N-No.
没准我就是疯婆子  但我有很充分的理由
Well, maybe I am crazy, but I have a damn good reason.
把线索联系起来啊  你个笨蛋
Connect the dots, you dummy.
我穿着这么松垮的衣服  我急需用钱
I'm wearing real loose clothes. I need money real bad.
我的头发像狮鬃一样有光泽
My hair is lustrous like a lion's mane.
你恋爱了吗
Uh, you're in love?
不  正相反  我怀孕了
No, the opposite! I'm pregnant!
好吧  我的天啊
Okay. Oh, God.
家里人不想让我和博复合
The family didn't want me to get back together with Beau
因为他是六分之一外地人还已婚
on account of he's six-parts Chicopee and married,
但我还是和他复合了  现在他进了监狱
but I did it anyway, and now he's in County
因为他照骑警马的脸上打了一拳
for punching a police horse in the face.
如果家里发现了  他们就会知道
And if they find out, then they'll just know
所有人说我是废物真是一点都没错
that everyone was right about me being such a screw-up.
小帕  我一点都不知情
Oh, Pam, I-I had no idea.
你怀孕几个月了
I mean, how many months along are you?
马上就生了
Oh, all of them.
想说就说吧  谴责我吧
Yeah, go ahead. Condemn me.
你那张平凡的脸上全是评判的表情
I can see the judgment all over that generic face of yours.
这根肩带像钢琴线一样割肉
This strap is cutting into me like a piano wire.
你介不介意去翻翻我的行李
Would you mind going through my luggage
帮我把晚餐后穿的胸罩找出来
and pulling out my after-dinner bra?
如果别无选择的话
If I must.
我回来了
I'm home!
我没选上  多谢关心
I didn't get picked. Thanks for asking.
我倒是有好消息
Well, I have good news.
米奇尔和我是赢得人或动物类最佳装扮
Mitchell and I are early contenders to win the best costume
的早期热门选手
in the human/animal category.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
用食物自我安慰
Self-comforting with food.
那蛋糕我做了一早上
I've been working on that all morning,
是为了晚上的派对准备的
and it is for a party tonight.
你们一群基佬又不会真的吃蛋糕
What are a bunch of gays gonna do with a cake
只会围起来叽叽喳喳夸蛋糕漂亮
but stand around screeching about how pretty it is?
好吧  我受够了
Okay, that's it.
小帕  你太无礼了
Pam, you are rude.
你太不尊重人了
You are disrespectful.
你居然还敢吃第二口
And you are going in for another bite?!
把叉子放下  放下
Put the fork down! Put it down!
是时候
It is high time
你开始也为其他人着想一下了
that you start thinking about somebody other than yourself!
你就是这么看我的是吧
Oh. So that's how you feel?
是的
Yes, it is.
那咱俩今天没完了
Then I guess it is on!
别  不要
Don't. No!
-你跑就对了  -别闹
- You better run! ‭- No!
从我身上下来  我还没准备好
Get off of me! I wasn't ready!
准备好接我这招
Then get ready for this!
快住手
Hey! Cut it out!
疼死了
Hey! That hurts!
很好  表示老娘打对了
Good, then it's working!
别演了  你个戏精  我都没碰到你
Oh, cut it out, you faker. I'm not even touching you.
我猜是这件吧  你这是干嘛
I assume it's this one. Oh, what are you doing?
她怀孕呢
She's pregnant!
什么
What?! ‭
别打了
Hey! Hey! Cut it out!
惨了  我羊水好像破了
Oh, no, I think my water just broke.
流在我身上了吗
Is it on me?!
我现在准备要下崽了
I'm fixing to reproduce right now!
打给811
Call 811.
米奇尔  别  那是牲畜急救电话
No, Mitchell, that's for livestock.
打911
Call 911.
我知道  我知道好吗
Yeah, I-I know. I know.
姐  你为什么没告诉我
Pamela, why didn't you tell me?
你觉得呢
Well, why do you think?
当然是不想让你失望啊
I didn't want to disappoint you.
你是我最崇拜的.....
You know you're the person I look up to mo-o-o-o-o-st...
-家人了  -是吗
- ...in the family. - ‭I am?
不然我为什么来这里
Why do you think I came here?
我希望生孩子时能在你身...
Oh. ‭I wanted to be near you when the baby po...
我想到如果我先找到份工作
But I thought maybe if I got a job first,
我看起来就不会那么失...败
I wouldn't look like such a pathetic me-e-e-e-ss!
怎么了
What?
我好冷啊  小卡
I'm so cold, Cam!
给  盖上米奇尔的熊戏服
Oh, oh, here, put on Mitchell's bear costume.
来  盖上
Here you go. Come on.
他们大概十分钟后到达
Okay, so they are gonna be here in, uh, 10 minutes.
我撑不到那时候了
I'll never make it!
孩子要出生啦
Okay. ‭It's a-coming!
好  米奇尔  米奇尔  来
Okay! Mitchell! Mitchell, okay.
没事的  我们都在这里陪你
It's all right. We're here for you.
帮忙我把她裤子脱下来
Help me get her pants off.
-好的  行  -然后我们得
- Okay. Yes. - ‭All right, we need to get
弄点枕头放到她屁股下
some pillows up underneath her hips
让她的产道维持正确的生产角度
to get her birthing canal properly angled.
好啦  我们准备
Yeah! ‭All right, here we go.
放轻松
Relax. ‭
米奇尔
Mitchell!
我想确保救护人员不会开过我们家
I want to make sure that they don't miss the house,
-所以我去...  -呼吸  呼吸
- so I'm just gonna... - Breathe, breathe.
弗兰克与洛林  今天是你们公开与合法地
Frank and Lorraine, today marks the public and legal
灵魂与灵魂结合  把婚姻置于一切之上的
joining of your souls, marriage being above all else,
签约仪式
a contract.
我最爱的其中一个作家曾写道
Uh, one of my favorite authors once wrote,
来自印度/英国文学家萨尔曼·鲁西迪爵士
"爱若不是一切  那便一文不值
"If love is not all, then it is nothing.
这个原则与它反面的不贞
This principle, and its opposite,
碰撞出了我一生多年来扣人心弦的故事"
collide down all the years of -- of my breathless tale."
看到菲尔在台上这么闷  我有一种母鸟
Seeing Phil bomb up there, I felt like a mama bird
在小鸟已长大  把它踢出巢时
who had just nudged her chick out of the nest
没先说个笑话让它忘了疼的自责感
without a single pun to break his fall.
"人没有了爱情就活不下去
"For man can no more survive without love
就像木桶工不能离开柴刀
than a cooper without his billhook,
补鲸人不能没有剥鲸油刀"
nor a whaler less his flensing knife."
这些真知灼言直到今日
Words as true today as they were
也与一万八千年前刚被写下时一样正确
when they were written 18,000 years ago.
这不太对啊
That can't be right.
现在到了我问在座各位
Now is the moment when I ask if anyone here
有没有人有任何理由反对他俩成婚的时候了
has reason to object to the union of these two people.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
我反对
I object!
我反对你没有把他们的钻戒交给我  牧师
I object to you not handing over those diamond rings, preacher!
听到她说的了没
You heard her.
把钻石交过来  否则让你们吃墙子儿
Hand over the ice, or I fill you full of...leed.
-是吃枪子儿  -亲爱的  你在干嘛
-Lead. -Honey, what are you doing?
抱歉牧师  吉时已过
Sorry, padre, you had your chance.
我宣布你正式死亡
I now pronounce you dead!
你什么时候...
When in the world did --
一个死人咋这么多问题呢
A lot of questions for a cadaver!
你们没看出来吗  这两个人是一伙的
Don't you see? These twos is in on it together!
少管闲事  贱人
Mind your own potatoes, Daisy.
不好意思
Excuse me.
这是老娘的婚礼
This is my wedding
与你们的丧礼
and your funeral!
小白脸也吃子弹吧
And one for the choir boy!
没中
Missed me.
你们还有兴趣再刷一个东西吗
Hey, uh, you guys feel like doing one more paint job?
不过这次是我们一起刷
Only all of us this time?
没问题
Sure.
有时人生比我们想得简单
Sometimes life can be simpler than we think.
我们出生...
We're born...
或许我们应该收留小帕与孩子
You know, um, maybe we should let Pam and the baby
在楼上住一阵子
stay upstairs for a little while.
米奇尔刚才说...  不对  他不喜欢我这样
Mitchell was just saying -- No, he hates when I do that.
我刚才在想  或许你跟孩子
I was just saying that maybe you and the baby
应该在我们楼上先住段时间
should stay upstairs for a while?
小卡
Oh, Cam!
我们去世
...we die...
你们是恶魔佳酿上脑  都疯了吧
You're all mad with the devil's brew!
来自1916年无声电影《再来一杯恶魔佳酿》
恶魔佳酿指的是鸦片
而在这之间
...and in between...
如果运气好  我们会有欢笑
Ah! ...if we're lucky, we laugh...
而这趟人生旅途也就值了
...which makes the journey worth taking.
听完这番话之后
With that in mind...
弗兰克·邓菲  我认识最傻气的一个人
Do you, Frank Dunphy, the silliest man I know...
愿意娶洛林来折磨她一辈子吗
...take Lorraine to be your long-suffering wife?
我愿意
I do.
你可以亲你的娘子了
You may kiss the tomato.
先生  你一个小时前就该上床啦
Your bedtime was an hour ago senor.
我想先读完这本书
I wanna finish this.
你都不认字
You don't even know how to read.
别担心了  楼上没有怪物
Stop worrying. There is no monster up stairs.
那漆很管用的
That paint works.
妈咪  你能去检查一下吗
Mommy, can you check it?
好啦
Okay.
你妈连这块又旧又粘的防水布都不让我丢
Your mother won't even let me get rid of this sticky old tarp.
她对什么东西都抱着不放
She's attached to everything.
很快你就会享受到这件事的好处了
Someday soon that will work in your favor.
小心那个水泥砖
Careful that cinder block.
拜托  你就是推也推不动它
Man, you couldn't budge that thing with it.
棒  这下还有个沼泽怪物了
Great, now I have a swamp monster.